Guide to the James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers TAM 347
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series XIV: Writings, Published.
  - Subseries XIV:A: Articles (In Chronological Order)
    - "New Program of the Communist Party U.S.A." (James E. Jackson co-author, Published by CPUSA); "Report on the World Conference of Communist and Workers Parties" ( Party Affairs, Vol. 3, No. 14); "Separatism - A Bourgeois - Nationalist Trap" ( Party Affairs, Vol. 3,. No. 4); "World Revolutionary Strength and the Nature of Our Epoch" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLVIII, No. 3), 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Lenin and National Liberation" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLIX, No. 5); "On Seizing Time" ( Party Affairs, Vol. IV, No. 3);"On the Lenin Centenary" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XLIX, No. 2); "On Socialist Countries and the Class Struggle" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLIX, No. 8), 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "About Three Philosophers" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 1); "All Power to the Communist Party of Venezuela" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 5);"National Liberation: An 'October' Dream Fulfilled" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 7-8); "To The Communist Party of India" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLV, No. 12), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "90th Birthday of Georgi Dimitrov" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LI, No. 8); "Excerpts from Speech at the 20th Convention on Maoist Ideology" ( Party Affairs, Vol. LI, No. 7); "Theory of the Chicano Question" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Special Supplement to Party Affairs, Communist Party Jan 1972); "USSR - A Design for Good Living in a Multi-National State" ( Party Affairs, Vol. LI, No. 9) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "The CPUSA: 54 Years Old" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. LII, No. 9); "For Safeguards Against the Party's Enemies" ( Party Affairs, Vol. VII, No. 1); "The Meaning of Watergate" ( Information Bulletin, Vol. 11, No. 13-14), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Foreword" in Ethiopia's Revolution; "A Talk to Teachers of Marxism" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LIII, No. 4), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "With Confidence in Our Cause" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LIV, No. 2), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Address to the Socialist Unity Party" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LV, No. 7); "Dr. Hyman Lumer: Communist... Dedicated Worker... Hero" ( Jewish Affairs, Vol. 6, No. 4), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - The Communist Party - the Mind, the Will and the Honor of the Working Class ( Political Affairs Reprint); "Lenin's Party Precepts Affirmed by History" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XVI, No. 11); On Certain Aspects of Bourgeois Nationalism ( Political Affairs Reprint); "Pages from the History of Struggle in the South Report on Portuguese Party Congress" ( Party Affairs, Vol. 11, No. 2); "Lenin's party Precepts Affirmed by History" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 11); "Pages From the History of Struggle in the South" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 2), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "The Afro-American Struggle - Introduction" ( Party Organizer, Vol. XIII, No. 3); "An "Appreciation" ( Jewish Affairs, Vol. 9, No. 1); "Charting the Path to Equality" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XVIII, No. 11); "Draft Resolution on Afro-American Liberation" ( Black Liberation Journal, Vol. 3, No. 2); "The Meaning of this Anniversary" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XVIII, No. 8-9); "On the 60th Anniversary of the CPUSA - Yours in Struggle" ( Party Organizer, Vol. XIII, No. 6); "The Working Class: Hub of the Nationalities Wheel" ( Black Liberation Journal, Vol. 3, No. 3-4; ( Party Organizer, Vol. XIII, No. 12), 1979 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Black Liberation and the Socialist Perspective" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 4); "From Contributions by Conference Participants" ( Socialism: Theory and Practice, Novosti Press Agency); "Kampuchea: Resurrection of a Nation" Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 7); "The Eternal Flame of Ho Chi Minh" Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 7); "Leninism - Marxism's Universal Teaching" Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 6); "October's Child is Humanity's Champion" Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 11); "The Working Class: Hub of the Nationalities Wheel" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LIX, No. 2), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "The Correlation Between Theory and Policy" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LX, No. 7); "XXXVI. CPSU Congress Highlights - Peace Now for People's Progress" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LX, No. 4), 1981 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "Israel War Crimes: International Aspects" ( Jewish Affairs, Vol. 12, No. 5); "Leonid Brezhnev - In Memoriam" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. LXI, No. 12); "Reaganomics in Nationalities Policy at Home and Abroad" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXI, No. 10); "Reaganomics and the Fight For Peace" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXI, No. 6); "Workshop - IV - Reaganomics and the Fight for Peace" ( Party Organizer, Vol. XVI, No. 4,5,6), 1982 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Affirmative Action and the Fight for Equality" ( Black Liberation Journal, Vol. 6, No. 1); "A Book for All Good People" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXII, No. 10); "From Teachings of Karl Marx for the United States" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXII, No. 4-5); "Peace Relates to the Everyday Concerns of People" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXII, No. 7-8), 1983 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "Marxist Theory of the Negro Question" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. LXIII, No. 2), 1984 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "Every Tenth Man - A WWII Document" Political Affairs, Vol. LXIV, No. 2); In The Struggle Always Political Affairs, Vol. LXIV, No. 7), 1985 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "The Destructive Design of The Color Purple ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXV, No. 6); "The Journey of Martin Luther King" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXV, No. 2), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "Open Greeting" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXVI, No. 9); "In Memory of Henry Winston" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Information Bulletin, Vol. 25, No. 5-6), 1987 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Intermediate Strategic Stages" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXVIII, No. 8); "W.E.B. Du Bois: Light of the Path" ( Political Affairs, Vol. LXVIII, No. 7), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "Progress Report From the Program Committee: Special Remarks" ( Reports and extended remarks to the National Committee/National Council meeting Communist Party, USA, New York City, August 4-5, 1990); "Special Remarks" ( Equality and Empowerment Part II (Conference Proceedings,New York City, October 13-14, 1990) (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Subseries XIV:B: Leaflets.
    - Leaflets, Undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Subseries XIV:C: Pamphlets (In Alphabetical order).
    - 3 Brave Men Tell How Freedom Comes to An Old South City - Nashville, Tenn., 1963 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - The Afro-American Struggle - A Draft Resolution, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Anti-Sovietism: Preparation for Global Suicide, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Communist Call to Africa, Undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Gus Hall: The Man and the Message, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - How Socialism Will Come to the United States - Viewpoint of the Communist Party, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Karl Marx and the United States, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Marxism and Negro Liberation (by Gus Hall and annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship;, New York: New Century Publishers), 1951 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - The Meaning of Black Power, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - The Negro Question in the U.S.A., 1966 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - The Philosophy of Communism, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Riding to Freedom, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Some Aspects of the Negro Question in the United States, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - The South's New Challenge, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Stalin's Thought Illuminates the Problems of Negro Freedom Struggle, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - The Struggle for Afro-American Liberation, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Theoretical Aspects of the Negro Question in the United States - Supplement to Party Affairs (New Features of the Negro Question, Draft Resolution, National Committee Discussion), 1959 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - A Tribute in Tears and Thrust For Freedom - At the Funeral of Medgar Evers, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - USSR - A Mighty Union of Nations, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Watts Upsurge - A Communist Appraisal, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Will There Be Socialism in The U.S.A.?, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 42)
- Series XV: Writings, Unpublished.
  - Afghanistan, Undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Africa, Undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - African-American History, Undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - African-American Issues, Handwritten notes, Undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - African-American Issues, Manuscripts, Undated, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - African-American Issues, Manuscripts, Undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Algeria, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - American History c. 1865, Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Americans For Democratic Action - Meeting Notes, Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - An American Soldier's Thoughts on World Freedom - Pages From a Soldier's Diary, ca.1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Andropov, Yuri Vladimirovich, Undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Angola, Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Monopoly Coalition, Undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Berlin, Undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Black Belt, Undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Black Liberation, Undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Black Liberation - A Manuscript 1., Undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Black Liberation - A Manuscript 2., Undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Black Prisoners, Undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Book Reviews Written by James E. Jackson, Undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Bourgeois Nationalism, Undated, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Burnham, Louis, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Callahan Act, Undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Capitalism, Undated, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Carter Administration, Oil Shortage, Undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Chicano, Undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Chile, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - China, Undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Churchill, Winston, Undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Clarke, John Henrik, Undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Class Struggle, Undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Class Struggle and African-Americans, Undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Cold War, Undated, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - The Color Purple(by Alice Walker), Undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Communist and Workers Parties, Conference of, Undated, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Communist Party, 1 of 2, Undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Communist Party, 2 of 2, 1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Communist Party - Education, 1947-1948, Undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Communist Party - Election Campaigns, 1968, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Communist Party - International Affairs, 1968, Undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Communist Party - Negro Question, Undated, 1954-1972 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Communist Party Policy on African-Africans, History of, Undated (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Communist Party - Programs, 1935, 1935, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Communist Party (Reports, Proposals, Memorandums), 1935, 1952-1983 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A. and the Mexican Communist Party, meeting, Undated, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Communist Party - Virginia Convention, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Corvalan, Louis, Undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Crockett, George, Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Cuba, Undated, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Angela, Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Benjamin, Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Democracy, Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Party Convention, Undated, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Dennis, Eugene, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Dennis, Peggy, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Detroit: Jackson as Party Organizer in Automobile Industry, Undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Detroit UAW Local 600 Anti Speed-Up Strike, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Dialectical Materialism, Undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Dialectics of National Liberation - M.A. Thesis, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The Dialectics of National Liberation - M.A. Thesis Notes, Undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Dominican Republic, Undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B., Undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Engels, Frederick, Undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Ethiopia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Far East, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - First Amendment, Undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Flight 1, Plane Crash, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Forest, William, Undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Freedom of the Press, Undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Gates Doctrine, Undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Gene's [Dennis] Report, Undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Ghana, Undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Greetings, Appreciations, Undated, 1960s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Grenada, Undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Hall, Gus: Discussion Outline on Main Street to Wall Street: End the Cold War (Attributed to Jackson), 1962 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Hall, Gus: Speeches and Writings Written by James E. Jackson, Undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Hemispheric Conference, Undated, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Historical Materialism, Undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Hungary, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Imperialism, Undated (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - India, Undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - International Communist Movement, History of, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Interview with Edward L. Patton, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Interview with Nguyen Duy Trinh: "Vietnam on Paris: Hope Without Illusion", Undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Interview with Mao Tse Tung in China and Related Notes, 1959, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Interview with Yang Chien Jen, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Interviews given by James E. Jackson, Undated, 1959, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Israel, Contemporary Zionism, Undated, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Jackson, Jesse, Undated (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Jim Young's Plan - Memorandum to a Publisher From a Writer about a Book, Undated (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Johnson, Lyndon, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Jonestown Tragedy, Undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Kennedy, John F., Undated (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Kennedy's Armament Program / Budget, 1963? (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - King, Martin Luther, Undated, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Kolkin, Alex, Undated (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Labor Movement, Undated (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Latin America, Undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Lebanon, Undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Lenin, Leninism, Undated, 1970, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Line of March (organization), Undated (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Maoism, Undated (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Marcuse, Herbert, Undated (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - A Manuscript / Collection of Speeches and Articles, 1951-1961 (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - A Manuscript / Collection of Speeches and Articles, 1951-1961 (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - May Day, 1958, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Marxism - Leninism, Undated, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - McCarran Act, Undated (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Mental Development and Learning Disability, Undated (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Mexico, Undated (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Michigan Negroes for Wallace, Undated (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Middle East, Undated (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - Militarism, Undated (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous Material, Excerpts, Undated (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Mission to Mobile, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Motion of Jim Jackson to Suspend John Gates from CP's National Administrative Committee, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - National Bourgeoisie in the Semi-Colonial and Colonial Country, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - National Question, Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Native American Question, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Negro American Labor Council, Undated, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Negro Question, 1941-1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Negro Question - Coercive Christianity, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Negro Question - handwritten notes and manuscripts, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Negro Question - manuscripts, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Negro Youth, Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - New Features of the Negro Question, 1960 (?) (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Our Battle for the Ballot, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Patterson, William, Undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Peace, Undated, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Political Economy, Undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Poverty, Undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Prague, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rico, Undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Racism, Undated, 1977-1986 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Richmond, Al and Healey, Dorothy, Undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Robeson, Paul, Undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Russian Revolution, 1917, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Salt II Treaty Between the U.S. and the Soviet Union, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Slavery in Britain, Undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - So He's Been Discharged by Sgt. and Mrs. James E. Jackson, ca.1945-1946 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Socialism, Undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Song for Africa, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - South, 1936-1960 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - South - Farm Crisis, Undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - South - Fight Against McCarthyism, Undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - South - Handwritten Notes and Manuscripts, Undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - South - Manuscripts, Undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - South Africa, Undated, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - South Korea, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Southern Front Now! and other typescripts on the Communist Party and African-Americans, ca.1950s (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Soviet Union, 1959-1976 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Soviet Union, Undated (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Stalin's Thought Illuminates Problems of Negro Freedom Struggle, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Strong, Ed, Undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Syria, Undated (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Task at the Present Stage of the Struggle Against Imperialism and United Action of the Communist and Workers' Parties and all Anti-Imperialist Forces, Undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Teachers of Marxism (Outline), Undated (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Textile, Undated (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Titov, Gherman, Undated (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Trade Unions, Undated (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - The Trial of Emmet Hill, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Tribute to Our War Dead, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - United Auto Workers, Undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - U.S. Economy / Capitalism, Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Internal Political Affairs, Undated, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam, Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam - Uncle Ho, Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Watergate, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - White Chauvinism, Undated, 1949, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - White Liberals, Undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Whose Conspiracy?, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Winston, Henry, 1960, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Women Sterilized in Virginia, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Women's Question, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - World War II, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Working Class, Undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - World Peace Council, Undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Series XVI: Writings by Others.
  - Subseries XVI:A: American, West European Writers.
    - Book Reviews of James E. Jackson's Books, Undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Author Unknown: The Louisiana Election, Undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Author Unknown: The Nature of German Fascism, Undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Author Unknown: The Negro Press - Democratic Heritage, ca.1940s (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Author Unknown: The Negro Question (no title), Undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Author Unknown: Scandalize My Name - A Singer's Memoir Regarding the Robeson Family and Protest Music, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Abt, John: Recent Developments in the Fight for Party Legality, Undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Ades, Bernard: The Elections and Civil Rights, Undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Almberg, Mark: The Old Bug of Right Opportunism, Undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Amana, Harry: The FBI and the Black Press, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Aptheker, Herbert, Undated, 1958, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Barron, John: The KGB's Magical War for 'Peace', 1982 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Bart, Philip: Black Socialist Pioneers and an Untitled Work, Undated, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Bary, Art and Bell, Pat: Pamphlet on the Mexican-American People of the Southwest, Undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Becchetti, Arnold: Untitled Speech, Undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Benello, George C.: Organizing for Change: Notes Toward a Theory of Organization, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Bennett, Lerone: The Challenge of Blackness and an Untitled Work, Undated, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Bert, Erik: Report to the National Negro Commission; The Web of Finance Capital, 1968, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Bloice, Carl: Black Liberation; Notes for NC Meeting Remarks, Undated, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Briggs, Cyril: For a Marxist Position on the Negro Question, Undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Brutens, Karen: National Liberation Movement, 1966, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Buchanon, Joe: A Dead-End Detour from the Class Struggle - Steve Nelson, American Radical, 1981? (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Burke, John, Donald: The Origin of the Family (a play), Undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Burnham, Louis, Undated, 1946-1960 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Cameron, Kenneth: Shelley and Marx, Undated (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Cardenas, Lazaro (untitled work), Undated (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Chapman, Frank E. Jr: Pages from the Life of a Black Prisoner; On Marxism-Leninism and the Struggle for Penal Reform, Undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Clarke, John Henrik: Response to James E. Jackson's Article, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Cohen, Barry, Undated, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Coleman, Morris: Reynolds vs. Hoffman; A Concept of the Ideal; Biography and Obituary, Undated, 1976, 1978-1981 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Davis, Angela: Racism and Male Supremacy, untitled work, Undated, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Degrood, David, H.: The Crisis in Contemporary Philosophy and the Class Question, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Draves, Drew: The Gorbachev Revolution, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Du Bois, W.E.B., 1928, 1950s, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - Dutt, R. P.: Marxism and Mr. Strachey - On the Marxist Theory of Increasing Misery, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Eisenscher, Michael: Is There a Marxist-Leninist Party in Our Future?; The Indispensable Ally: Black Workers and the Formation of the CIO, 1992, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Eisenscher, Sig: Some Comments on the Role and Future of the Committees of Correspondence, Undated (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Escalante, Annibel: A Speech (no title), Undated (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Everling, Clark: Connecting the Links in the Value Chain, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Faria, Jesus and Ponce, Guiellermo Garcia: The Fourth Congress of the Communist Party of Venezuela in Defense of the Leninist Principle, Undated (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Feldman, Jennie: When I Joined the Communist Party, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Felix, Leon: Report from Commission on Manhattan, Undated (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - Fichtenbaum, Myrna: The Funsten Nut Strike, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - Fichtenbaum, Rudy: Marx's Theory of Economic Cycles, Undated (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - Filardo, Al: Pre-Convention Discussion Article, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Fishman, Joelle: Build Unity to Take Back Our Country in 2004! Defeat Bush and the Ultra Right; untitled work, Undated, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - Foster, William Z., Undated, 1958, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 61)